Betselot Getnet Semaw

Software Engineer

Highly skilled and experienced full-stack developer with a passion for learning, teaching, and helping others. Strong proficiency in React and Node.js and a general understanding of the stack including Redux, Saga, Styled-components, Webpack, Koa, and REST/GraphQL. Demonstrated success in providing technical support and developing complex web applications. Excellent communication and presentation skills.

| \succeq | betselotgetnet2227 | <mark>/@gmail.com</mark> |
|-----------|--------------------|--------------------------|
|-----------|--------------------|--------------------------|

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/betselot-getnet-2423561aa/

+1 613 452 1407

https://github.com/Betselot-GA

Work experience

Software Engineer

Repibox, April 2022 – Present | US

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to develop and maintain complex web applications using React, Node.js, and related technologies.
- Designed and implemented reusable components, optimized performance, and ensured accessibility for users with disabilities.
- Troubleshot and resolved technical issues, providing support to users and other developers.

Frontend Engineer

Ethiopian Public Health Institute, Mar 2022 – July 2022 | Ethiopia

- Built and maintained dynamic websites using React, Node.js, and related technologies.
- Developed custom components and optimized website performance for a better user experience.
- Provided technical support to users, resolving issues and ensuring high levels of customer satisfaction.
- Contributed to the development and implementation of new features and functionalities.

Junior Developer

Tefer Consolidate, August 2021 - April 2022 | Ethiopia

- Developing developers lesson plan for Online learners on MongoDB, Express, Angular and Node.
- Debugged and Fixed Front end applications developed with AngularDart and Angular.

Education & Learning

BSC in Software Engineering

Addis Ababa Institute of Technology, 2018 – 2024

- Fullstack Software Development
- · Mobile application programming
- DataStructures and Algorithm
- IT security
- Advanced Database Management System

Global UGRAD Scholarship Program Delta State University | US

World Learning - August 08,2022 - December 08,2022

Top 2% Scholarship receiver for a 1-semester exchange program in the US from Agust 08,2022 to December 08, 2022 . Astronomy | Modern Programming | Project Management | American History

Competitive Programming

Africa to Silicon Valley, August 2021 - August 2022

A2SV upskills high-potential African students, connects with top silicon valley companies, and creates digital solutions to urgent problems in their home countries. The first group of A2SV students achieved a 59% (13/22) success rate at Google internship interviews for summer 2021.

Organizational Leadership

ShARE, April 2021 - Present

- Vice President of ShARE AAU/AAiT 2022 Program
- Leadership, Consultation, Slide making, Communication skills

Work experience

Software Engineer

Botaye, September 2021 – December 2021

- Designed and implemented new features to improve website's user experience, resulting in a 10% increase in conversions
- Collaborated with designers and stakeholders to ensure that the website meets accessibility standards
- Utilized Git for version control and collaborated on code review with other team members

Projects

Kendel Digital Magazine: Link

designed and developed full-stack digital magazine

website to post, download & blog magazines , with Postgres & nextjs

Sudoku Solver: Link

A python application developed with pygame designed to solve and play Sudoku game.

Special Education: <u>Link</u>

A react web application developed for Special Education giver company to schedule and manage appointments.

Tech Stack

Languages:

Html, CSS, Javascript, Java,
 C#, Python

DBMS

- MongoDB, MySQL, Postgresql
 Frameworks
 - Bootstrap, Tailwind, Angular, Flask, React, ASP.Net, Nextjs

Mobile Dev

Flutter, Kotlin

Volunteer and Extra Curricular

Web designer and Social Media Curator

TedX AddisKetema, Oct 2021 – May, 2022

Deputy National Coordinator

East African Regional Office for Astronomy, April 2020 - March 2022

Volunteer Coordinator

Ethiopian Space Science Society, Sept 2018 - Present

Maed Charity Organization

Cofounder, President, july 2020

Event and marketing department head

Hult Prize Foundation, Sep 2020 – Dec 2020 |Ethiopia

Marketing Associate

Mn Ale Addis, Sep 2020 - Aug 2021 |Ethiopia

Awards and Certificates

- · Youth Space Ambassador
- Won first place creating safe schools for girls.
- Certificate of Achievement: Microsoft 4Afrika
- Certificate of Completion to introduction to Rocket and Satellite Engineering.
- Certificate of Recognition from International Astronomical Search Collaboration
- Certificate of Achievement-The 2021
 Ethiopian Collegiate Programming
 Contest